<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on Balasubramanian Venkat</title>
    <link>/bvenkat/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on Balasubramanian Venkat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/bvenkat/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Manager, Program Director</title>
      <link>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-01/</guid>
      <description>Polaris Financial Technology &amp;amp; Intellect Design Arena Ltd., Mumbai and Chennai, India. June 2011 &amp;ndash; Feb 2017.
 Program director for our global transaction banking implementation for one of the largest public sector banks in India. This was the first implementation on Jboss application server and the first ever implementation of our Transaction banking product in India.
 Program Manager for Liquidity Solution implementation for one of the largest Globally recognized Financial services Firm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Manager, Project Manager</title>
      <link>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-02/</guid>
      <description>Cambridge Solutions, Bracknell, UK and Chennai, India. May 2008 –- Sep 2010.
 Senior Delivery Solutions Manager for DHL Supply Chain Application.
 Senior Delivery Manager for the Enterprise Systems Integration team and Supply Chain Integration team, managing about 130 members in the team. Key responsibilities were to streamline the team, manage and strengthen the delivery capabilities for DHL Supply Chain account.
 Onsite IT Program Manager for DHL managed around 10 projects in the Enterprise services Integration area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independent Consultant</title>
      <link>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-03/</guid>
      <description> Sep 2007 &amp;ndash; Apr 2008.
 Provided Project management consultancy for Nuveda Learning Pvt. Ltd.
 Managed engineering &amp;amp; delivery of e-learning packages for Multi location rollouts.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Manager, Program Director</title>
      <link>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-04/</guid>
      <description>Polaris Software Lab Ltd., India, Japan &amp;amp; UAE. July 1998 – April 2007.
 Program Manager.
 Turned around a program (Hire Purchase and Lending Suite implementation) that had cost overruns for the previous 3 years. Managed a first full-fledged implementation of the Polaris’s flagship product Intellect which involved data migration from the legacy system, interfaces to external payment and printing systems and extensive workflow integration for transactions in the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Independent Consultant</title>
      <link>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-05/</guid>
      <description>Independent Consultant, Cheltenham, U.K, and Chennai, India. Feb 1995 –- June 1998.
 Project Manager.
 Developed a Campaign Management Tool in United Kingdom for insurance companies.  System Analyst.
 Developed PC based solutions for Small to medium sized enterprises in and around Chennai.  Consultant for a leading systems integration company in Chennai.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmer and Systems Analyst</title>
      <link>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bvenkat/projects/contributions/job-06/</guid>
      <description> Synergy Login, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. May 1994 –- Jan 1995.
 Programmer
 Developed an Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) project for retailers in Malaysia.  Systems Analyst
 Developed a Limits Monitoring System for the finance department of ESSAR Group of Companies in India.   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>